low testosterone symptoms and low
thyroid symptoms are basically the same
in
man he's 20 5'8 142 pounds I guess I
sleep for 8 to nine hours I still feel
energyless every time I wake up no
morning wood for the past year I don't
even remember when I had my last one
libido is also extremely low I started
to go to the gym for past six months
calculated diet yet gained majority fat
only decided to get my test levels uh
got to know I have extremely low levels
180 nogan per deciliter what advice
would you give
me okay so if he wasn't so light I would
be saying you know so if people are
going to extrapolate this out for their
own learning in a scenario like this for
anyone else it's very important to not
just look at testosterone but also look
at the thyroid because low testosterone
symptoms and low thyroid symptoms are
basically the same in men the whole like
you have to have cold extremities thing
for thyroid not really the primary
symptom that we see when it's mild and
subclinical a lot of the time it's this
like just fatigue Lethy anhedonic kind
of stuff that we see with low
testosterone now given this guy is is
quite light but I mean he did also say
that he's calculated his diet and he's
putting on fat the most important thing
this guy can do and and I sound like a
broken record saying this because it's
it's the only real answer to a lot of
these questions where guys are looking
for very personal here are my stat
here's my Bloods what should I do the
first thing you have to do is get a more
comprehensive lab panel because a good
provider will want to assess everything
thyroid adrenal hormones um you know
obviously your full Androgen panel as
well things like your liver your kidneys
your lipids your red blood cells white
blood cells your diet your lifestyle all
of this stuff is really important in
determining what's going on the most
important thing well not the most
important thing but one of the most
important things that this gentleman
could do is have a provider assess where
his G tropin are so if his lutenizing
hormone is suppressed like a two or
under he could have a cause of low
testosterone that he can resolve without
needing to go on trt but if he's got you
know mid-range gonadotropin or even
elevated gonadotropin suggesting damage
to the gonads then he is he's going to
want to get those testosterone levels up
because those are terribly low levels
for a man of any age especially a young
man and it would be virtually impossible
for someone to thrive and feel good on
those levels so if he's applying himself
he's doing everything right it's very
important that he sits down with a
provider who can go through everything
but also give him a recommendation
that's going to be based on what's in
his best interest not based on what they
want to sell him or what kind of you
know ulterior motive they might have to
be able to give a recommendation but
this is something that he absolutely
needs to get thoroughly investigated but
the most important thing for anyone in
this kind of scenario is to have
everything investigated at once because
I often see guys in these scenarios
who've got fatty liver disease they've
got Hashimoto hypothyroidism um they've
got just massive issues with diet and
lifestyle you know they're following
something like a vegan diet or they're
doing something that's just not
conducive to their health that they
don't really understand what's wrong so
this needs to be further investigated
and absolutely resolved and it may
require trt